UHCL Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership (BAHEP) Records
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
UHCL Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership Records
1976-2009
Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership (BAHEP)
2010-0001
8 linear feet
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
The Nassau Bay Garden Club collection documents the organizational records of the Nassau Bay Garden Club from 1964-2000.
Administrative History
The partnership was originally incorporated in May 1976 as the Clear Lake Area Economic Development Foundation (CLAEDF) by a core group of merchants and corporation executives to promote business, tourism, and the continued development of the Space Program in the Clear Lake area. In 1995, the name changed to Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership (BAHEP), to signify the wider expanse of influence and development which was no longer limited to the Clear Lake Area, and included many of the communities along the Gulf Coast around Houston.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection contains 15 boxes of materials pertaining to the development of the Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership (BAHEP), formerly known as the Clear Lake Area Economic Development Foundation (CLAEDF), from its beginning in 1976 to 2009. CLAEDF and BAHEP operated as promotional marketing and development agencies for businesses in the Bay Area and its communities. The collection includes organizational histories, minutes, newspaper articles, press releases, promotional brochures, events, awards, photographs and magazines. It should be noted that the Executive Committee minutes and handouts from 1991-1996 were donated by Joe D. Barlow from his personal papers.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 11 series:
Series 1: Organizational History
Series 2: Meetings
Series 3: Reports
Series 4: Business Development,
Series 5: Newsletters
Series 6: Newspaper Articles, Press Releases
Series 7: Events
Series 8: Awards
Series 9: Photographs and Images
Series 10: Oversized Magazines
Series 11: Oversized Newspapers
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Abbey, George, 1932-; Andrews, Mike; Barlow, Joe D.; Bostick, Jerry; Brooks, Jack, 1922-2012; Brown, Lee; Covey, Richard (Dick); Goldin, Daniel Saul, 1940-; Hutchison, Kay Bailey, 1943-; Lampson, Nick; Lee, Sheila Jackson; Reinhardtsen, Jim; Richards, Ann, 1933-2006; Staples, William A.
Subjects (Organizations)
Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership (BAHEP); Clear Lake Area Economic Development Foundation (CLAEDF); National Keep It Sold (NKIS)
Subjects
Economic Development of Bay Area Houston; Marketing of Bay Area Houston; Quasar Award
Places
Bay Area Houston; Clear Lake City (Tex.); Ellington Air Force Base (Tex.); Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated by the Bay Area Houston Economic Partnership (BAHEP) in 2009.
Other Finding Aid
UHCL Chancellor (Neumann) Records, 1990-0002
UHCL Chancellor (Stauffer) Records, 2000-0007
UHCL President (Stauffer) Records, 1999-0007
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series 1: Organizational History
  - History of BAHEP: The First Thirty Years 1976-2006--Chronology (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History of BAHEP: The First Thirty Year 1976-2006-Research of Data (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws, May 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Advertising and Promotional Proposal, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Development Letters, March-Dec 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Meetings
  [These meeting files were removed from binders and have been kept in their original chronological order, 1976-2008.]
  - Board of Trustees and Directors Meetings, and Project papers, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meetings, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meetings, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - International Business Ventures Committee, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Board Meetings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meetings, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board Meetings, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reassessment Committee Meetings, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meetings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Executive Committee and General Membership Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series 3: Reports
  - Annual Reports (includes 2004-2006 reports on compact disc), 1986-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - CLAEDF Progress Reports, 1991; 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Commission on the Future of the United States Aerospace Industry, Final Report, Nov. 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fundraising Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - JSC Annual Economic Impact Report, 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Summary of NASA Budget Request, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series 4: Business Development
  - Bay Area Business Development Scrapbook, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Business Developers Roundtable, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - CLAEEF Directory of Members, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ellington Field Task Force, 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Houston Chronicle Tour & Bay Area Houston, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Marketing and Media Plan, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Marketing Scrapbook, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Video from Continental Airlines, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Technology Outreach Program (TOP), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series 5: Newsletters
  - Business to Business, November 1998-December 2007, 1998-2007 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Business to Business, January-December 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chemicals and Commodities Articles, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - CLAEDF Compass, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - CLAEDF Foundation Forum, 1985-1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clear Lake Area Notes, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Clear Lake Area Promotional Magazines, 1989; 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Foundation Flash Newsletter, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series 6: Newspaper Articles, Press Releases
  - Articles, press releases, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Articles, press releases, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Articles, press releases,1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Articles, press releases, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Articles, press releases, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Articles, press releases, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Articles, press releases, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Articles, press releases, January-March 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Articles, press releases, April-June 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Articles, press releases, July-September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Articles, press releases, October-December 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Articles, press releases, January-December 1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Articles, press releases, January-July 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Articles, press releases, August-December 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 2002 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 2002 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Articles, press releases, January-December 2003 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Articles, press releases, January-December 2004 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Articles, press releases, January-December 2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Articles, press releases, January-December 2006 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Articles, press releases, January-December 2007 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Articles, press releases, January-June 2008 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Articles, press releases, July-December 2008 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Series 7: Events
  - Appreciation Luncheon for Houston Council Member Addie Wiseman, Oct. 17, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - BAHEP Image Launch, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Banquet Brochures, 1987; 1998-2000,; 2005-06 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Challenger Seven Benefit Concert & Reception, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Citizens for Space Exploration, SATOP, Washington, DC, May 2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Elected Officials Luncheon, Sept. 12, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Harris County Commissioner Candidate's Forum, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - St. John Hospital Tenth Annual Gala Benefit Under The Big Top, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Series 8: Awards
  - Award Banquets CDs, 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Clear Creek Independent School District Appreciation To CLAEDF, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Quasar Award Banquet honoring Dr. William A. Staples, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Quasar Awards Banquet honoring Houston Mayor Lee Brown (includes audio tapes), 2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Series 9: Photographs and Images
  - Aerospace Panel, August 19, 1992 (6 photos) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Aerospace Task Force Breakfast, Nov. 11, 1986 (10 photos) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Aircraft Belts, Inc. Groundbreaking (6 photos), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Architect's Drawing, John Crane Bldg, October, 1989 (1) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Armand Bayou Slides, 1996 (35 slides) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Australian Ambassador Luncheon, April 25, 1986 (7 photos) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Awards Banquet, February 16, 2005 (7 photos) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - BAHEP Launch, (Renaming), 2003 (100 photos) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Bostic, Jerry (1 photo), undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Brazil ECA October 30, 2000 (13 photos) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Businesses (6 photos), 1995-97 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - CLAEDF Event, Nassau Bay Hilton, (6 photos), circa 1996 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - CLAEDF Events, Banquets, 1989 (17 photos) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - CLAEDF Faces, (6 photos), undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - CLAEDF Group Photo, Texan Style show (2 photos), circa 1990 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Clear Lake Chamber of Commerce 30 Year Award to Boeing, 1997 (13 photos) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Command and Control Technologies (CCT) Graduation, May 2000 (8 photos) (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Breakfast, February 10, 1986 (29 photos) (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Congressman George Brown fundraiser, May 8, 1992 (1 photo) (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Congressman Jack Brooks Tribute,1994 (45 photos) (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Congressmen Jack Brooks, Mike Andrews, and Tom Delay Tribute, Aug. 1994 (22 photos) (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Evans, Bud Presentation, Space Commercialization (19 photos), undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Environmental Resource Awards, April 25, 1994 (4 photos) (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Farnborough Air Show, July, 2000 (43 photos, logo) (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Gillebaard, Frans (1 photo), undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Goldin, Daniel S. Day, October 14, 1994 (50 photos) (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Grumman Orientation program, November, 1986 (34 photos) (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - HISD At Risk Children's tour JSC May 19, 1992 (2 photos) (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Johnson Space Center Aerial, 1989 (negative, description), 1986 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - KIWO banquet January 1999 (14 photos, negatives) (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Library of Congress Meeting (10 photos), undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Library of Congress NKIS Meeting, c. 1999 (56 photos), circa 1999 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Local Business Presentations (25 photos), 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Local Businesses slides (38 slides), 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Membership Meeting, May 25, 1986 (8 photos) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - NKIS (National Keep it Sold) Meeting (possibly) (15 Photos), circa 1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - NKIS Meeting (10 photos), 1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - NKIS Meeting (possibly) (46 photos), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - NKIS and other events in Washington DC and Library of Congress, May 4, 2004 (82 photos) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - NKIS Meeting in Washington DC, Library of Congress, with Dick Covey (14 photos), undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - NKIS and Unitech, Feb. 1999 (6 photos, negatives) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Paris Air Show (13 photos, negatives), circa 1994 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Paris Air Show, June 1997 (61 photos) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Peat Marwick Reception, August 29, 1985 (7 Photos) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Petrochem Plant, negative only, circa 1989 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Petrochem Taskforce Jan 1999 (13 photos, negatives) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Quality of Life Housing slides (62 slides), circa 1989 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Quasar Award to George Abbey (96 photos), circa 1997-2004 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Quasar Award to Governor Ann Richards (4 photos), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Quasar Award to Senator Kay Bailey Hutchison Aug. 1996 (3 photos) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Reinhardtsen, Jim, New CLAEDF President, June 1992 (11 photos, negatives) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - ROBEXS (Robotics and Expert Systems) Breakfast, June 27, 1985 (14 photos) (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - ROBEXS (Robotics and Expert Systems) Breakfast, June 5, 1986 (12 photos) (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - SATOP (Space Alliance Technology Outreach Program) (4 photos), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Save Our Space Station Meeting (47 photos), 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sonny Carter Facility (3 photos), circa 1993 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Space Camp Scholarship, Spring 1991 (1 photo) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Space Expo, 1991 (3 photos) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Spacework Presentation, July, 1986 (6 photos) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - St. John Hospital Tenth Annual Gala Benefit Under the Big Top, (3 photos), 1993 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Takachiho Kohiki Company visit July/August, 1992 (3 photos) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Technological Research & Development Authority (TRDA) (1 photo), circa 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Telly Award, October 1998 (8 photos, negatives) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Texas Chiropractic College (TCC) Dedication, April 7, 2006 (2 photos) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Texas Workforce Check Presentation to San Jacinto College, August 31, 2000 (1 photo) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Tribute to Elected Officials, October 11, 1996 (94 photos) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Washington, D.C. Event, 1994 (15 photos) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Washington, DC meeting 1995 (6 photos) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Welcome AMOCO Employees Banquet, c. 1994 (6 photos), circa 1994 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified Airfield & Plane, 1994 (photos) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified Event at Nassau Bay Hilton with George Abbey (110 photos), undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified Event at Space Center Houston with Kay Bailey Hutchison (32 photos), circa 1993 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified Event at Space Center Houston with Sheila Jackson Lee (7 photos), circa 1993 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Event at UHCL photos, c.1993 (10 photos), circa 1993 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified Event at UHCL photos, c.1993-95 (10 photos), circa 1993-95 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Unidentified Event at UHCL with Daniel Goldin (22 photos), 1994 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified Event with Mike Andrews (10 photos), circa 1993-94 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Event with Sheila Jackson Lee (9 photos), undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Events, circa 1995-2000 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Unidentified Events, circa 1995-2000 (Box 14A, Folder 26-29)
- Series 10: Oversized Magazines
  - Bay Area Houston Magazine, Oct. 2004-Jan. 2007 (Box 15)
  - Baycomber, Jan. 2001; June 2003 (Box 15)
  - Expansion Solutions, June-July 2003 (Box 15)
  - LifeStyles of Galveston Bay Magazine, Jan. 2007 (Box 15)
  - Pasadena LifeStyles Magazine, Jan. 2007 (Box 15)
  - SouthEast LifeStyles Magazine, June 2003; Jan. 2007 (Box 15)
  - Tierra Grande, Apr. 2003 (Box 15)
- Series 11: Oversized Newspapers
  - The Citizen, March 8, 1995; Feb. 22, 2007 (Box 15)
  - Greater Houston Weekly, Aug. 27, 2003 (Box 15)
  - Houston Chronicle, June 20, 1993; July 2005 (Box 15)
  - Houston Post, Apr. 26, 1993 (Box 15)